<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feels on Nikhil&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/categories/feels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feels on Nikhil&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.nikhil.sh/categories/feels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Critic Awakens</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/12/22/the-critic-awakens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/12/22/the-critic-awakens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🚨 SPOILER ALERT 🚨&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start this off by saying that I&amp;rsquo;m not a movie critic. I caught The Force Awakens the day it came out, even though I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not a huge fan. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched all the movies twice, but I don&amp;rsquo;t remember the model of the Millennium Falcon, or the name of Anakin&amp;rsquo;s owner back on Tatooine. I&amp;rsquo;m someone who enjoys the first three movies, plot wise, as I grew up on it, and cannot imagine not knowing Obi-Wan when he was younger or Anakin before he became a rage monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I believe JJ Abrams was under a great amount of fan pressure while directing the movie, and he did very well. The Force Awakens was a good movie, although I wonder if Abrams relied a bit too heavily on the fan favorite characters from the previous movies. Darth Vader&amp;rsquo;s mask did not seem to add much to the movie. The flying scene with the X fighters destroying the &amp;lsquo;death star&amp;rsquo; seemed all too familiar. And of course the Death Star v2.0 itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only gripe with the movie was the casting of Kylo Ren. I did not feel the power from him. I know that this partly was because Kylo Ren hasn&amp;rsquo;t truly fallen, but Kylo&amp;rsquo;s voice and actions did not seem intimidating. Even Darth Maul, the Sith Lord that many people did not like, had more character. I hope the next few movies work on Kylo Ren a bit more, and shape him to be a worthy successor of Darth Vader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just had to air my feelings about those few things but the movie itself was great, and had everything I had hoped for (maybe more lightsaber action would be cool :))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun catching the movie if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, but then you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have read this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p align=right&gt;written by @MeNikhil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>