<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nikhil&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nikhil&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 19:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.nikhil.sh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/08/28/gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 19:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/08/28/gaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dota2.com/international/overview/&#34;&gt;The International 5&lt;/a&gt; is upon us now, and most Dota players are stuck at home, glued to their screens and just watching teams of 5 battle it out for millions. The prize pool now stands at $17.6 million dollars (and rising), surpassing prize pools of major sporting tournaments like the Super Bowl and NBA finals. Why then is eSports still being looked down on as just something nerdy teenagers play because they don’t have other things to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dota_2&#34;&gt;Dota&lt;/a&gt; player myself, I can only offer my opinion on the matter from an Action RTS standpoint.This might sound pretty cliche, but Dota to me, is more than just clicking a mouse quickly. From the subtle mechanics, to the mind games, to the synergy with your teammates, and of course, reaction times make this game more than just a game. Even with thousands of hours played, Dota still offers something new every time you boot a new game out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dota has a very steep learning curve, and it never seems to plateau out, which makes for a very exciting game. People who have just a couple of hundred of hours under the belt, are able to best people who have spent 3000 hours in game. It is an interesting game where you have to be thinking constantly and always outplay your opponent. In that regard, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=55fBpL1IFvU&#34;&gt;Dota is very similar to chess&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about eSports is also the sheer number of people who watch competitive gamers play. Tickets for The International 5, hosted in Seattle’s Key Arena, sold out within minutes, with people coming from all over the world just to watch their favourite team battle it out for the title of being the best team in the world. All this hoohah for a game that is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UjZYMI1zB9s&#34;&gt;free to play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world in general is recognising eSports now. With Amazon paying $1 Billion to grab &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitch.tv&#34;&gt;Twitch.tv&lt;/a&gt; from under Google’s nose, to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ycombinator.com/instant-esports-yc-s15-is-espn-for-competitive-gaming&#34;&gt;YC&lt;/a&gt;’s funding of an eSports startup, eSports is getting bigger. Perhaps one day, we gamers will be able to shed the negative image that associated with gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://profile.ak.fbcdn.net/hprofile-ak-snc4/372835_154528731324940_863073820_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Typical Gamer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![../../static/images/neckbeard.jpg]()&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p align=right&gt;written by @MeNikhil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/08/27/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 19:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/08/27/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to make a blog for sometime, in order to just get back to writing, like I used to do when I was younger. This would also serve as a project for me, as I am not too familiar with working with the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with Jekyll, for a bit, when I was making some changes on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rebel.tools&#34; title=&#34;Rebel Tools&#34;&gt;Rebel Tools&lt;/a&gt;, and it was pretty fun so I did consider using Jekyll for this blog. However, I chanced upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which is a static HTML generator in Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with Hugo as it is fast (way faster than Jekyll), and it seems cool to try out a new technology!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zyro/hyde-x&#34; title=&#34;hyde-x&#34;&gt;Hyde-X&lt;/a&gt;, an enhanced port of the Jekyll &lt;em&gt;”Hyde”&lt;/em&gt; theme, as it’s simple and looks clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pretty simple to set this blog up. I don’t think that this steps are in the correct order, but it worked :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new GitHub repo, and switch the default branch to gh-pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir themes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd themes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/zyro/hyde-x&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the config.toml file in order to edit content that will be generated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And then you just need to run &lt;code&gt;hugo --theme=hyde-x&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd into the public folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add origin git@github.com:username/repository&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m message&lt;/code&gt; to commit locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push origin gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; to push to github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to set up a custom domain, there are different steps to take if you were to set up as a project site versus as your main site. Do read up on GitHub for help with that. As this is a project site, I went to my domain registrar, added a CNAME record that pointed to &lt;code&gt;nikhilsh.github.io&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; as the host. I then went over to the folder named static and added a CNAME file there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s basically it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p align=right&gt;written by @MeNikhil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/license/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;content-license:53e892b8b41cc4caece1cfd5ef21d6e7&#34;&gt;Content license&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All non-code blog content is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-license:53e892b8b41cc4caece1cfd5ef21d6e7&#34;&gt;Code license&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All source code files and snippets found on this blog, unless otherwise explicitly noted, are licensed under the terms below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Copyright 2015 Nikhil Sharma

Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &amp;quot;License&amp;quot;);
you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
You may obtain a copy of the License at

   http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
distributed under the License is distributed on an &amp;quot;AS IS&amp;quot; BASIS,
WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
limitations under the License.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#whoami</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;strong&gt;Nikhil Sharma&lt;/strong&gt;. I am an iOS developer working for &lt;a href=&#34;http://cubiclerebels.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cubicle Rebels&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m a junior
in Singapore University of Technology and Design, pursuing a degree in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;contact-me:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Contact me&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find me on &lt;a title=&#34;twitter&#34; href=&#34;http://twitter.com/menikhil&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&#34;Linkedin&#34; href=&#34;http://sg.linkedin.com/in/iamnikhil&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop me a mail at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@nikhil.sh?Subject=Hello%20there&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;me@nikhil.sh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#links</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-collection-of-some-of-my-frequently-used-links:424069113a08a4256349764ee38dbbbf&#34;&gt;A collection of (some of) my frequently used links.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// # DNS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// * &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intodns.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;intoDNS&lt;/a&gt;- Check DNS health
// * &lt;a href=&#34;https://w3dt.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;World Wide Web Domain Tools by ITOC Australia&lt;/a&gt;- DNS and Web tools&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>