<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nikhil&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nikhil&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 22:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.nikhil.sh/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/09/18/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 22:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/09/18/music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me, knows that I am an Apple fanboy. Naturally, when Apple Music launched back in June, I immediately terminated my Spotify premium subscription that I had been using for slightly over 4 months. Apple Music’s promise of tight integration with iOS, and with Beats 1’s promise of being a radio that would never be turned off, and being managed by people who loved music, I was ready to make the switch. I was excited to finally listen to Taylor Swift, even though I’m not a huge fan, but the fact that I hadn’t heard it on Spotify enticed me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s music onboarding was something that was talked about as being an interesting UI experience, and I have to agree that it was interesting. Was it good from a UX point of view? I would say no. It took forever to go through the genres, and the genres were already little as it was. There was no metal, no subgenres of anything, and somehow, K-pop, M-pop and other asian related music kept popping up. I mentioned that I liked K-pop but loved Rock, but Apple insisted on recommend me dozens of K-pop bands. I get that I am in Singapore, but that doesn’t mean I just like Asian music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Music feedback mechanism was also not to my taste. I didn’t like the fact that I had to tell Apple what music I liked with the heart buttons. I have been an iTunes Match subscriber for years and they should have known what music I own, but no, I had to tell Apple exactly what songs I liked. I’m sure that Apple was tracking my plays, and therefore tried to guess the songs I liked even though I had not favourited them. In either case, the heart button was, to me, utterly useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beats 1. I can’t entirely blame this on Apple, as apparently MDA was blocking them from broadcasting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://discussions.apple.com/thread/7105059&#34;&gt;Someone&lt;/a&gt; contacted MDA, and apparently Apple was the one who didn’t contact them. We can’t trust this random forum comment, but in either case, the fact is, Beats 1 isn’t in Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My biggest gripe with Apple Music is their playlist recommendations. They are horrible. Horrible. Maybe this is because I didn’t favourite every single song, but I did favourite a significant amount. The ‘Recommend Less Like This’ button in iTunes did jack shit. Finally after 3 months, I decided that Apple Music just wasn’t ready yet, at least for me. I then decided to go back to Spotify and within 10 minutes, and 2.5 songs later, I knew I made the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spotify’s Discover Weekly worked. It just worked. I wasn’t forced to ‘heart’ songs that I liked, or kick songs out that I didn’t like. It just simple worked. Playlists were awesome. There were so context sensitive. Burning the midnight oil? No problem, here’s a mix to keep you going. Lazy sunday afternoon?  Here’s a mix to keep you relaxed. I had no idea how much I missed my friends feed as well. If I had wanted to keep my music to myself and not discover new songs, I would just buy albums off iTunes and listen to them offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, Spotify isn’t perfect, there are many songs that aren’t on Spotify, and I hope they are working out reasonable deals with artistes. There’s a reason Taylor Swift chose to go with Apple Music and not Spotify. Spotify’s UI also has room for improvement. I don’t like that my playlists are so cluttered. It makes me think twice about adding playlists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose Spotify after going on a break for three months for a variety of reasons, and I’m really sad that Apple Music failed for me, but Apple is going to work very hard to bring us Spotify users over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p align=right&gt;written by @MeNikhil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/07/28/gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 19:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/07/28/gaming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dota2.com/international/overview/&#34;&gt;The International 5&lt;/a&gt; is upon us now, and while thousands gather at the Key Arena in Seattle, most Dota players are stuck at home, glued to their screens and just watching teams of 5 battle it out for millions. The prize pool now stands at $18 million (and rising), surpassing prize pools of major sporting tournaments like the Super Bowl and NBA finals. Why then is eSports still being looked down on as just something nerdy teenagers play because they don’t have other things to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dota_2&#34;&gt;Dota&lt;/a&gt; player myself, I can only offer my opinion on the matter from an Action RTS standpoint. This might sound pretty cliche, but Dota to me, is more than just clicking a mouse quickly. From the subtle mechanics, to the mind games, to the synergy with your teammates, and of course, reaction times, make this game more than just a game. Even with thousands of hours played, Dota still offers something new every time you boot a new game out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dota has a very steep learning curve, and it never seems to plateau out, which makes for a very exciting game. People who have just a couple of hundred of hours under the belt, are able to best people who have spent 3000 hours in game. It is an interesting game where you have to be thinking constantly and always outplay your opponent. In that regard, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=55fBpL1IFvU&#34;&gt;Dota is very similar to chess&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about eSports is also the sheer number of people who watch competitive gamers play. Tickets for The International 5, hosted in Seattle’s Key Arena, sold out within minutes, with people coming from all over the world just to watch their favourite team battle it out for the title of being the best team in the world. All this hoohah for a game that is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UjZYMI1zB9s&#34;&gt;free to play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world in general is recognising eSports now. With Amazon paying $1 Billion to grab &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitch.tv&#34;&gt;Twitch.tv&lt;/a&gt; from under Google’s nose, to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ycombinator.com/instant-esports-yc-s15-is-espn-for-competitive-gaming&#34;&gt;YC&lt;/a&gt;’s funding of an eSports startup, eSports is getting bigger. Perhaps one day, we gamers will be able to shed the negative image that associated with gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://profile.ak.fbcdn.net/hprofile-ak-snc4/372835_154528731324940_863073820_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Typical Gamer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p align=right&gt;written by @MeNikhil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/07/27/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 19:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nikhil.sh/blog/2015/07/27/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to make a blog for sometime, in order to just get back to writing, like I used to do when I was younger. This would also serve as a project for me, as I am not too familiar with working with the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked with Jekyll, for a bit, when I was making some changes on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rebel.tools&#34; title=&#34;Rebel Tools&#34;&gt;Rebel Tools&lt;/a&gt;, and it was pretty fun so I did consider using Jekyll for this blog. However, I chanced upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which is a static HTML generator in Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with Hugo as it is fast (way faster than Jekyll), and it seems cool to try out a new technology!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zyro/hyde-x&#34; title=&#34;hyde-x&#34;&gt;Hyde-X&lt;/a&gt;, an enhanced port of the Jekyll &lt;em&gt;”Hyde”&lt;/em&gt; theme, as it’s simple and looks clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pretty simple to set this blog up. I don’t think that this steps are in the correct order, but it worked :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new GitHub repo, and switch the default branch to gh-pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir themes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd themes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/zyro/hyde-x&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit the config.toml file in order to edit content that will be generated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And then you just need to run &lt;code&gt;hugo --theme=hyde-x&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cd into the public folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add origin git@github.com:username/repository&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m message&lt;/code&gt; to commit locally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push origin gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; to push to github&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to set up a custom domain, there are different steps to take if you were to set up as a project site versus as your main site. Do read up on GitHub for help with that. As this is a project site, I went to my domain registrar, added a CNAME record that pointed to &lt;code&gt;nikhilsh.github.io&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;code&gt;blog&lt;/code&gt; as the host. I then went over to the folder named static and added a CNAME file there too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s basically it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;p align=right&gt;written by @MeNikhil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>